Kainan Doneson

Woodstock, NY, 12498 | 805-284-3987 | kaindoneson@gmail.com

Github: kainan54 | Medium | LinkedIn

Website: kainan.io

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby and JavaScript-based programming. Created projects with React and Rails frameworks. Background in retail and service industries, with strong teamwork skills from working with diverse groups of individuals. A passionate learner who is excited to help innovative companies solve problems and achieve goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Libraries/Frameworks: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, TypeScript

Other: Github, DOM, JSON, Effective Communication, Team Oriented

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ARt App - Github | Video Demo

ARt App is a web app that enables users to share images and view them in 3D and AR. Users can also interact through likes, comments, and followers

- Used React/JS for frontend and Rails API/Ruby for backend
- Enabled users to interact through photo uploads, likes, and following each other using rails models
- Applied Three is Library to make a 3D viewer that users could apply to uploaded images
- Incorporated AR.js to make a view layer where users can view their images with a hiro marker and webcam
- Leveraged Three.js library to make a 3D viewer that users could apply to uploaded images

GeoTunes - Github | Video Demo

Geotunes is a web application designed to allow users to create and share custom Google Maps routes that are linked to Spotify playlists.

- Used React/JS for frontend and Rails API/Ruby for backend
- Integrated Google Maps to enable users to make custom routes on a shared map
- Applied Spotify React Components to enable users to attach public playlists to custom routes
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and Bcrypt Gem for user authorization from frontend to backend

Flappy Demon - Github | Video Demo

Apple WTC

Flappy Demon is a loot-based web game where players collect items/power-ups by defeating enemies or by purchasing them from the item shop. Users are ranked based on the amount of currency gained from selling items.

- Used Phaser3/Vanilla-JS for frontend and Rails API/Ruby for backend
- Meshed dom elements to respond to Phaser3 game logic
- Utilized Rails API to persist player items and rankings

EXPERIENCE

 Lounge 247
 Manhattan NY

 Barback/tender
 02/2019 - 03/2020

Manhattan, NY

01/2018 - 11/2018

- Interacted with customers and prepared beverages for high-volume bar patrons
- Checked customers identification to ensure compliance with all beverage regulations
- Maintained bar and storage areas and restocked bar inventory and supplies

Back of House Specialist

11/2018 - 01/2019

- Rotated various back of house tasks with teammates to keep inventory organized and accessible
- Received product shipments and cataloged them for easy retrieval
- Documented, labeled, and shipped out product returns/repairs to the main depot

Retail Specialist

Interacted with customers to target technical needs and suggest product solutions

- Advised customers and provided guidance and assistance on setting up their new technology
- Maintained visual merchandising and stayed updated on new products and initiatives

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Brooklyn, NY
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 08/2020 - 11/2020